Okay, let's turn the tables on Bootstrap Tables.
接下来让我们把普通的表格转化成 Bootstrap 的表格
We'll talk about Bootstrap support for tables using the Bootstrap classes.
我们将学习如何用 Bootstrap 类来定义各种表格
Now when tables were first introduced into HTML, they were meant for
当表格最初被引入到 HTML 中时
displaying tabular data on a webpage.
它们使用来在网页上呈现表格状的数据的
Tables have been hijacked for
然而有时表格会在许多其它场合下被"盗用"
many other purposes, something completely other than tabular data.
在一些完全和呈现一张表格数据无关的场合
We have seen people using tables for
我们已经见过人们
formatting contents to be displayed on their pages.
用表格来给它们网页上的内容排版
Those were the days when we had no other means of
不过当时的我们确实没有其它的办法
controlling the display of content on our webpages.
来控制这些内容的排版
Now with the advent of grid systems like the Bootstrap grid,
现在 由于有了像 Bootstrap grid 这样的网格系统
I don't see any more reason to continue using tables for
我觉得我们就不应该再用表格
matching content on their pages.
来进行内容的排版了
Now this is one of my pet peeves, but anyway, aside from that,
事实上我很讨厌这种做法
let's talk about tables as they're originally intended for.
不管怎么说 我们还是讨论一下 表格最初的用途吧
Which is to display tabular data on our webpages.
亦即 在网页上呈现表格数据
In HTML of course, the table tag is meant for displaying tabular data.
HTML 里的 table 标签当然是用来显示 一个表格数据的
Bootstrap supplies
而 Bootstrap 所提供的一个叫 table 的类
a class called the table class which you can apply to the table tag.
则是用来应用到 HTML 的 table 标签上的
Now you are wondering, why do we need a table class for a table tag?
你可能会想 为什么我们除了 table 标签外 还需要 table 类呢
A table tag is itself a table.
事实上 一个 table 标签仅仅代表了一个表格而已
Now Bootstraps intention for using the table class use to make it very clear that
而 Bootstrap 的 table 类则会让这个表格 符合某种样式
this table is actually being used to format tabular data in their pitch.
这个样式在显示表格数据时 毫无疑问 是相当漂亮的
That's the reason why they provide the table class.
也就是说如果你想快捷方便地创建一个漂亮的表格 用 table 类将是一个很好的选择
So we would always see Bootstrap's
因此我们常常看到 Bootstrap 中的表格
formatting of tables starting with the table class.
用 table 类来设计版面
Besides the table class,
当然除了 table 类
we have many other table classes available within Bootstrap.
在 Bootstrap 中还有很多其它的类 可以拿来定制表格
So along with table, you should be using either table-striped,
比如说 table-striped
table-bordered, table-hover, table-condensed and table-responsive.
table-borderd, table-hover, table-condensed, table-responsive 等等
Now among these, in the exercise, we will look at the use of table-striped.
而在我们的练习里 我们将会 学习 table-striped 的使用
This creates tables with zebra striped rows meaning that alternate rows have
这个类会创建一个背景颜色灰白相间的表格
somewhat darker color than the other rows.
意味着这一行的背景颜色是浅色的话 上一行和下一行的背景颜色则会是深色的
So that we can more easily distinguish between the rows within the table.
这样就能更简单地区分表格中的各个行
Table-bordered class puts borders onto the tables.
table-bordered 类则会给表格添加边框
So in case you want tables with borders in place,
所以如果你需要一个带边框的表格的话
then you could use the table borders.
你就可以使用 table-bordered 类
Table-hover works in this way,
table-hover 类 顾名思义 会对你的鼠标位置作出响应
when you use your mouse to touch on any of the rows of the table.
当你用鼠标移动到表格中的某一行时
Then that row will be highlighted for you.
那一行就会被高亮显示
You can use table-condensed if you want to reduce the amount of cell padding
而如果你想减少单元格边距的话 你可以使用 table-condensed 类
that is standard in Bootstrap tables.
而这也是 Bootstrap 表格中的标准类
If you are using tables and you want your table to be responsive.
你还可以用 table-responsive 来创建一个 响应式表格
Meaning that when the table is viewed on
也就是这么一个表格 即使它处于 不同的页面大小中
extra small screens you still want the table to be fairly well displayed.
它也能很漂亮地进行其内容的呈现
Now on extra small screens that is screen sizes less than 768 pixels,
比如在一个小于 768px 的很小的屏幕中时
the table is turned into something that can be scrolled horizontally.
响应式表格将会自动具有横向滚动的功能
So if your entire table is unable to fit the screen, then Bootstrap will allow that
因此 如果你的响应式表格不能适配当前屏幕时
table to be scrolled in order to be read properly by the users.
Bootstrap 的 table-responsive 将会支持滚动功能 从而用户可以更好地阅读其内容
In addition, we have five classes that can be used for
除此之外 我们还可以通过五个类
coloring the table rows, as well as table cells.
来给表格的行或者单元格着色
There are classes are active, success, info, warning and danger.
这些类就是 active, success, info, warning 和 danger
We have already seen these in the context of collage, these adjectives being used.
我们之前其实已经学习过这五个类了
So you can apply these to either the table rows, or
所以我们可以类似地将这些类应用到表格的行
individual cells within your table.
或是单独的单元格中
This completes our discussion of tables and Bootstrap table classes.
以上 就完成了对表格和 Bootstrap table 类的讨论 【翻译 - Carefree0910】